Now that we've got our first three strings on our low E string, A string and D string.
I'm going to show you, I'm going to have to flip the guitar around to do this side.
It's almost the same; it's kind of the opposite motion.
Some guitars you don't have to worry about this problem.
On this guitar which is a Gibson, typically the tuning pegs, there?s three on one side and three on the other side of the headstock.
On a Fender guitar they will all be on one side, so you really won't have to worry about this step.
To do the G string, B string and high E string, I'm going to move to this side because it just makes it a little easier.
I'm going to start with the G string, by the way it is important to know in case you don't, that from the top of the guitar down you want to make sure you get the right strings in the right spot.
It's low E string, A string, D string, G string, B and high E string.
Now we're going to put our G string on, same thing as before put it in that slot on the tail piece.
The string goes through the saddle, the groove in the saddle there.
We're going to take this up to the top tuning peg, once again you want to hole ninety degrees and we're going to slide it in from the inside.
It's the same as this side, just kind of the opposite motion.
Leave a little slack, wrap it around and underneath pull it tight, hold it tight, pull it up, make sure it's sitting in the groove with the nut and tighten.
I'm going to finish up these strings and then I'll take you to the next step.